spec.org 2018-12-27

# SPEC Privacy Policy

**Benchmarks**

  * Cloud
  * CPU
  * Graphics/Workstations
  * ACCEL/MPI/OMP
  * Java Client/Server
  * Mail Servers
  * Storage
  * Power
  * Virtualization
  * Web Servers
  * Results Search
  * Submitting Results

**Tools**

  * SERT
  * PTDaemon
  * Chauffeur WDK

**Order Benchmarks**

  * Purchase Benchmarks
  * Downloads

**SPEC**

  * About SPEC
  * Membership
  * Awards
  * Press Releases
  * Trademarks
  * Fair Use Policy
  * Upcoming Events
  * Contact

**Mirror Sites**

  * FTP/HTTP

**Resources**

  * Site Map
  * Site Search
  * Site Index
  * Glossary
  * Performance Links

|   

Effective May 25, 2018 

##  Privacy Notice Table Of Contents: 

  * Recent Privacy Policy Updates
  * Our Commitment To Privacy
  * The Information We Collect
  * How We Use Information
  * Our Commitment To Data Security
  * Our Commitment To Children's Privacy
  * How To Access Or Correct Your Information
  * Changes to this Privacy Policy
  * How To Contact Us

* * *

## Recent Privacy Policy Updates

  * **May 2018**
    * Added GDPR provisions.
  * **July 2011**
    * SPEC and research partners may use aggregated and anonymized data for additional site traffic analysis.
  * **April 2009**
    * Order-related contact information (email and/or mailing address) may be used to contact customers regarding available updates to their licensed products
    * Policy may be amended from time to time with notice posted on the SPEC website
    * Removed paragraph regarding use of information provided when signing up for notices of new products and services, as sign-up is not currently available. Any such data collected prior to this update remains covered by previous policy statements.

##  Our Commitment To Privacy 

Your privacy is important, to you, to us, to anyone you may come in contact with. To better inform you so that you can protect your privacy, we provide this notice explaining our online information practices and the choices you can make about the way your information is collected and used. To make this notice easy to find, we make it available from our homepage and at every point where personally identifiable information may be requested 

##  The Information We Collect 

This notice applies to all information collected or submitted on the SPEC web site.

We do not commonly use cookies, or other session tracking methods, on this web site. However, some of our downloads ask a short survey and we do use a cookie to record whether or not the user has already completed this survey. This cookie can be refused or deleted with no ill effect other than being asked to re-fill the survey upon the next download.

Our comment and survey forms request your name and an email address that can be used to contact you. Some pages on this site provide online forms where you can order products, make requests, and register to receive materials. Our product order forms require your name, company information, billing and shipping addresses, as well as email and telephone contact information.

##  The Way We Use Information 

We use the information you provide about yourself when placing an order to complete that order. We do not share this information with outside parties except to the extent necessary to complete that order. We also use the supplied contact information to notify you about new releases and changes to benchmarks for which you are licensed.

We use return email addresses to answer the email we receive. Such addresses are not used for any other purpose and are not shared with outside parties.

We use our system logs, non-identifying information, and aggregate information monitoring for maintaining and improving our web site and our services. For example, we do review internally which areas of our web site get visits, and at what time, and from what Internet domains. Little of this information is specific to individual behavior, we make no attempt to identify any individual's behavior, and no individual information is ever shared with any 3rd parties. We and our research partners may also perform further analysis of site access patterns or traffic using aggregated and anonymized information from the system logs.

Finally, were we ever to use or share any personally identifiable information provided to us online in ways unrelated to the ones described above, we would first provide you an opportunity to opt-out or otherwise prohibit such unrelated uses.

##  Our Commitment To Data Security 

To prevent unauthorized access, maintain data accuracy, and ensure the correct use of information, we have put in place appropriate physical, electronic, and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information we collect online.

Furthermore, we do not store any individualized or sensitive data on any of our Internet servers. We do not even store any individualized financial information on any server within our domain.

##  Our Commitment To Children's Privacy 

No part of our web site is structured to attract anyone under 13 and we do not collect any information that might reveal a visitor's age.

##  How You Can Access, Correct, or Remove Your Information 

You can access all your personally identifiable information that we collect online and maintain by contacting us directly; see our contact information. For your safety, we do not keep any of this personally identifiable information online.

You can correct factual errors in your personally identifiable information or request removal of that information by sending us a request that credibly shows the error and/or your authority over the material in question. To protect your privacy and security, we will also take reasonable steps to verify your identity before granting access or making corrections.

## Changes To This Privacy Policy

We may amend this privacy policy from time to time as we add new products and services, as we improve our current offerings, and as technologies change. If we make any material or substantive changes in our treatment of information collected at this site, we will notify you by posting a clear and conspicuous notice of these changes on our website and in this privacy policy.

##  How To Contact Us 

Should you have other questions or concerns about these privacy policies, please contact us or send us an email at [info@spec.org](mailto:info@spec.org).
